Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Economic and Social Justice TAM.599
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Economic and Socical Justice
2010-
TAM.599
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites: i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Economic and Social Justsice Movements, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library, which was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program (Library of Congress) and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. The collection contains periodically archived web sites of entities concerned with economic and social justice, including the defense of the welfare state, that reflect a left/progressive viewpoint. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Anarchism, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Related Archival Material
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Economic and Social Justsice Movements collection contains periodically archived web sites of entities concerned with economic and social justice, including the defense of the welfare state, that reflect a left/progressive viewpoint. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Distributive justice.; Social justice.; Social responsibility in banking.; Social responsibility of business.
- Economic and Social Justice
  - BanksterUSA, 7/16/2011-
  - Campaign for America's Future, 6/12/2010-
  - Center for Popular Economics (click on title of collection to access thisi website), 5/3/2011-
  - Center for the Working Poor (click on title of collection to access this website), 3/23/2010-
  - Color of Change, 7/7/2011-
  - Grassroots Immigrant Justice Network, 7/5/2011-
  - Highlander Research and Education Center, 6/23/2011-
  - One Nation Working Together, 12/22/2010-
  - Philadelphia Unemployment Project, 5/5/2011-
  - Physicians for a National Health Program (click on title of collection to access this website), 5/8/2011-
  - Physicians for Social Responsibility, 5/3/2011-
  - Picture the Homeless, 7/3/2011-
  - Public Citizen, 4/17/2010
  - smartMeme
  - US Social Forum 2010 (click on title of collection to access this website), 7/17/2010